Guide to the Natural Science Manuscripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Original accession
  - ARTHUR WILLIAMS WRIGHT (1836-1915)
    - Articles
      - "Report on Tests of Voltaic Cells of Mr. C. M. Thompson", 1887 (Box 6, Folder 245)
      - "Report on Bradley Dynamo" (Box 6, Folder 245)
      - "Experiments Upon the Cathode Rays and their Effects", 1896 (Box 6, Folder 246)
      - "On x-rays Accompanied by experimental notes, and x-ray pictures", 1896 (Box 6, Folder 247)
      - "The Induced Alternating Current Discharge Studied with Reference to Its Spectrum and Especially the Ultra-Violet Spectruml" co-authored by E. S. Downs, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 248)
      - "Biographical Memoir of Benjamin Silliman 1816-1885", 1911 (Box 6, Folder 248)
    - Articles by Others
      - George Chrystal: "Electricity", 1879 (Box 6, Folder 249)
      - Edward C. Pickering: "Applications of Fresnel's Formula for the Reflection of Light", 1873 (Box 6, Folder 250)
      - Guilford L. Spencer: "Report of Experiments in the Manufacture of Sugar at Magnolia Station, Lawrence, KA", 1887 (Box 6, Folder 251)
    - Biographical and Genealogical Material
      - Memoirs of AWW, 1915, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 252)
      - Newspaper clippings about AWW and family, 1864, 1885. 1896-1900, 1906, 1915, undated (Box 6, Folder 253)
      - Wright family genealogy, undated (Box 6, Folder 254)
    - Memorabilia
      - Calling cards, Miscellaneous notes. address book, undated (Box 6, Folder 255)
      - Certificates of membership for various organizations, 1879, 1884, 1893 (Box 6, Folder 256)
      - Photographs, undated (Box 6, Folder 257)
      - Poems, 1863, 1865-66, undated (Box 6, Folder 258)
      - Sketches in pen and ink and pencil, unsigned, 1870-71, 1878-80, undated (Box 6, Folder 259)
    - Scientific Material
      - Graphs and diagrams, 1899, undated (Box 6, Folder 260)
      - Illustrations of the total solar eclipse, July 29, 1878 (Box 7, Folder 261)
      - Memoranda of measurements of quartz plates for United States Government, 1887-88 (Box 7, Folder 262)
      - Miscellaneous notes, 1882, 1897-98, 1907, undated (Box 7, Folder 263)
      - Transactions of the Astronomical Observatory of Yale University, Vol. I, Part VI, 1902 (Box 7, Folder 264)
      - X-ray pictures and photographs, undated (Box 7, Folder 265)
    - Yale College
      - Fellowship in physics: eligibility and conditions, undated (Box 7, Folder 266)
      - Letter to Class of 1859 written by AWW, 1911 (Box 7, Folder 267)
      - Pamphlets about Class of 1859 and two copies of The Yale Banner, 1859, 1861 (Box 7, Folder 268)